carbon value circulation, including carbon asset conformation, the global carbon trading,
碳价值流通，包括碳资产构造、全球碳交易、
and automatic revenue sharing, combining with smart contracts supports pay-go remote control
自动收益分享，结合智能合约支持按需付费远程控制
and automatic revenue sharing, greatly reducing overseas operation costs.
自动收益分成，大大降低海外运营成本。
Our goal is to make every energy device a node in a decentralized Web3 world and integrating
我们的目标是让每一个能源设备成为去中心化 Web3 世界中的一个节点，并整合
energy green system into the Web3 value system and finally realizing energy inclusiveness
能源绿色体系融入Web3价值体系，最终实现能源普惠
and global energy equity.
和全球能源公平。
That's all.
就这样。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
So yeah, our panelists gave a very good example.
是的，我们的小组成员举了一个很好的例子。
So from the robot car, the smart vehicle to the open source chipset to the AI-based camera
因此，从机器人汽车、智能汽车到开源芯片组再到基于人工智能的相机
and also energy devices.
还有能源设备。
So we see that it's not just the hardware.
所以我们看到这不仅仅是硬件。
If the hardware can sense, can take the duration by the AI and can take the action, then we
如果硬件可以感知，可以通过AI获取持续时间并可以采取行动，那么我们
believe that this device, this hardware should have the machine ID, should have the machine
相信这个设备，这个硬件应该有机器ID，应该有机器
wallet and they must have the right to participate in the machine economy as the independent
钱包，他们必须有权利作为独立的人参与机器经济
economy agent.
经济代理人。
So yes, our panelists gave us the very good, you know, the use case, the example.
所以，是的，我们的小组成员给了我们非常好的，你知道的，用例，例子。
So we go to the next question and because we have the panel topic today is from the
所以我们进入下一个问题，因为我们今天的小组主题来自
device to the autonomous system.
设备到自治系统。
So the second question is, what do you see as the biggest challenge or the biggest opportunity?
那么第二个问题是，您认为最大的挑战或最大的机遇是什么？
Then we try to integrate the blockchain, the Web3 into the autonomous, the hardware, like
然后我们尝试将区块链、Web3 集成到自治硬件中，比如
the AI robot, the robot car, the open source chipset, the AI camera, the imaging equipment
AI机器人、机器人汽车、开源芯片、AI相机、影像设备
or the energy devices.
或能源设备。
So yeah, let's start with Ben.
是的，让我们从本开始吧。
Well I think the biggest challenge for us, for me, because we are relatively new to this
嗯，我认为对我们来说最大的挑战，对我来说，因为我们对此相对较新
Web3 world, but we saw this as our destiny because we know where we are heading.
Web3 世界，但我们认为这是我们的命运，因为我们知道我们的前进方向。
The biggest challenge is traditionally, I think, is for the native Web3 companies and
我认为，传统上最大的挑战是原生 Web3 公司和
then for the traditional hardware companies.
那么对于传统硬件公司来说。
I will speak from my perspective.
我从我的角度来说一下。
Yesterday, last year actually, we came over for the Fintech week that was much bigger
昨天，实际上是去年，我们参加了规模更大的金融科技周
and all the Token 2049 in Singapore, in Dubai, we see all the hot waves.
而所有的Token 2049在新加坡、在迪拜我们都看到了热浪。
Today is much more rational, but the major differences we saw, I saw this year is there's
今天更加理性，但是我们看到的主要差异，我今年看到的是
much more participation from the so-called traditional hardware company and also the
所谓的传统硬件公司以及
smart machine company.
智能机器公司。
I think for us, the biggest challenge for us is just to really understand the fundamental
我认为对我们来说，最大的挑战就是真正理解基本原理
logic of the Web3 world.
Web3 世界的逻辑。
When we believed in this, and then the next challenge for us is how, because all the traditional
当我们相信这一点时，我们面临的下一个挑战就是如何，因为所有传统的
machines and also the Web3 world, the crypto world, were not built for the human world,
机器以及 Web3 世界、加密世界，都不是为人类世界而构建的，
but the machine was built for the human world, but not built for the machine world.
但机器是为人类世界建造的，而不是为机器世界建造的。
So biggest challenge for us is how can we, this machine economy, can integrate the smart
所以对我们来说最大的挑战是我们这个机器经济如何能够整合智能
mobility and the smart machine and combine it into smart assets.
移动性和智能机器，并将其组合成智能资产。
But certainly, at the same time, it's also the biggest opportunity for us.
但同时，这对我们来说也是最大的机会。
I remember last year, I think it was eight months ago, when we were having this Fintech
我记得去年，我想是八个月前，当时我们有这个金融科技
week in Hong Kong, Leo and me, I think Du Yu and KK, a few others, we were sitting there,
在香港的一周，Leo和我，我想杜宇和KK，还有其他几个人，我们坐在那里，
and Leo showed me this X post from Vitalik.
Leo 向我展示了 Vitalik 的这篇 X 帖子。
That day, Vitalik, the speaker you're going to see in the next 20 minutes, he's the founder
那天，Vitalik，你将在接下来的 20 分钟内看到的演讲者，他是创始人
of Ethereum.
以太坊。
Basically, he posted an X on that day.
基本上，他那天贴了一个X。
If I remember correctly, he says, I really believe the open, verifiable, and autonomous
他说，如果我没记错的话，我真的相信开放的、可验证的和自治的
will be the key requirement to build a genuine machine economy.
将是建设真正的机器经济的关键要求。
So that's when we, I felt very excited by his statement, because he was saying exactly
所以就在那时，我对他的声明感到非常兴奋，因为他说的正是
what we wanted to do, because we, as a traditional smart machine company, we have a lot of application
我们想做的，因为我们作为一家传统的智能机器公司，我们有很多应用
scenarios, and if we can work with the blockchain companies, the Web3 companies, we can transform
场景，如果我们能和区块链公司、Web3公司合作，我们就能转型
the traditional application scenarios into open, autonomous, and verifiable, and foundation
将传统应用场景转变为开放、自治、可验证、基础
for the machine economy.
为了机器经济。
So for me, that's why we decided, after a week, we decided to invest in Akron.
所以对我来说，这就是为什么我们决定在一周后决定投资阿克伦。
When I was interviewed by one of his co-founders, he said, as a NASDAQ company, why are you
当我接受他的一位联合创始人采访时，他说，作为一家纳斯达克公司，你为什么
invested in this blockchain company?
投资这家区块链公司？
I said, look, we believe this is the future, because we treat this investment not only
我说，你看，我们相信这就是未来，因为我们不仅对待这项投资
as an investment, but like a token for the future, and almost for me, it's like a tuition
作为一项投资，但就像未来的象征，几乎对我来说，这就像学费
fee to learn from you guys.
向你们学习收费。
So that's how we see this.
这就是我们的看法。
Thanks, Ben.
谢谢，本。
So what's your opinion?
那么你有什么看法呢？
Sure.
当然。
In terms of the challenges, I guess this is what I see is, basically, if you really want
就挑战而言，我想这就是我所看到的，基本上，如果你真的想要的话
to enable edge devices to be able to have sufficient compute power, also not too much
让边缘设备能够有足够的计算能力，但也不能太多
of latency, to be able to do a lot of the cryptographic operations, I think there's
延迟，为了能够进行大量的加密操作，我认为有
we're still getting there, and I think we need to continue to invest in this open source
我们仍然在实现这一目标，我认为我们需要继续投资这个开源项目
space to help invent and improve technology that can actually does that.
空间来帮助发明和改进真正可以做到这一点的技术。
I think that's one of the challenges I still see, but I think once we get over that with
我认为这是我仍然看到的挑战之一，但我认为一旦我们克服了这个问题
the improvements in technology, I think the opportunities is huge.
技术的进步，我认为机会是巨大的。
With respect to being able to tie a lot of the assets, off-chain assets, to be able to
关于能够绑定大量资产、链下资产，能够
execute offline and then tie it back on-chain in terms of the settlement, et cetera, I think
我认为，离线执行，然后在结算等方面将其绑回链上
that's very exciting.
这非常令人兴奋。
Imagine a world where we have the assets be able to self-monetize some of their idle resource
想象一个世界，我们的资产能够将一些闲置资源自我货币化
and also compute storage, et cetera, to be able to really utilize that, and at the end
还有计算存储等等，以便能够真正利用它，最后
of the day, if they're able to do that, they can actually self-pay the hardware and get
如果他们能够做到这一点，他们实际上可以自行支付硬件费用并获得
over that initial hurdle, and then you'd be able to go into a very good positive loop
克服最初的障碍，然后你就能够进入一个非常好的正循环
in that.
在那。
I do think it's a great opportunity ahead while we are trying to figure out some of
我确实认为这是一个很好的机会，同时我们正在努力找出一些问题
the initial challenges.
最初的挑战。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I think they really need this kind of infrastructure from the vendor to create the chip-cell layer
我认为他们确实需要供应商提供这种基础设施来创建芯片单元层
for the whole crypto, the web-street, the industry.
对于整个加密货币、网络街、整个行业来说。
So how about Dijika?
那么迪吉卡呢？
I think the biggest opportunity is that blockchain can isolate devices into networks that can
我认为最大的机会是区块链可以将设备隔离到可以
share rules, identities, and such like we have lots of rings.
共享规则、身份等，就像我们有很多戒指一样。
We have an iWatch.
我们有一个 iWatch。
We have iPhones.
我们有 iPhone。
They are very smart, but it's a standstill intelligence.
他们非常聪明，但那是一种静止的智能。
In the future, when we build a smart device, we not build a single device smarter.
未来，当我们构建智能设备时，我们不会构建更智能的单个设备。
It's helping the whole network work better around identity, trust records, permission,
它帮助整个网络更好地围绕身份、信任记录、许可、
and insafes.
和保险柜。
But the biggest challenge is also clear.
但最大的挑战也很明显。
The physical world is a real-time where blockchains have latency and costs.
物理世界是实时的，区块链存在延迟和成本。
Many decisions must happen locally, especially in robots, cars, and wearables.
许多决策必须在本地做出，尤其是在机器人、汽车和可穿戴设备方面。
So I do not think that every action will go on-chain, but a better model is that the devices
所以我不认为每个动作都会上链，但更好的模型是设备
handle real-time sensing and collect data and do the cost.
处理实时传感并收集数据并计算成本。
With user permission, they also contribute to sensing, memory, or compute, and receive
经用户许可，它们还有助于传感、存储或计算，并接收
transparent record.
透明记录。
Because I work on the intelligence imaging and AI devices, I believe that the next generation
因为我从事智能成像和AI设备的研究，所以我相信下一代
of the hardware will not be defined only the better spats or bigger models.
硬件的定义不会只是更好的争论或更大的模型。
It will define who can truly connect to the hardware.
它将定义谁可以真正连接到硬件。
AI and services that run over time.
随着时间的推移运行的人工智能和服务。
And when the Ethereum and Wear 3 can help make this happen, I want the most of the concept
当以太坊和 Wear 3 可以帮助实现这一目标时，我想要充分利用这个概念
but a practical system that the device should not only sense and act, but each device, just
但一个实用的系统，设备不仅应该感知和行动，而且每个设备，只是
like the host, it owns the Wear 3 ID and the wallet.
与主机一样，它拥有Wear 3 ID和钱包。
To exchange the data, also collaborate and share value in the open network.
为了交换数据​​，还可以在开放网络中协作和共享价值。
Great.
伟大的。
You mentioned the very key part, the coordination, by the blockchain, by Wear 3.
您提到了非常关键的部分，即区块链、Wear 3 的协调。
So how about Kelly?
那么凯莉呢？
We have limited time, so yeah, please, I'll start with you.
我们的时间有限，所以是的，请我从你开始。
In our energy industry, we can buy so many things like PV, intelligent controllers, and
在我们的能源行业，我们可以买到很多东西，比如光伏、智能控制器、
energy storage, put our stations together.
能源储存，把我们的站放在一起。
Of course, in this kind of interrogation, we will meet huge challenges and opportunities.
当然，在这样的审问中，我们会遇到巨大的挑战和机遇。
About challenges, most IoT and hardware has low power and limited computing, which causing
关于挑战，大多数物联网和硬件的功耗低、计算能力有限，这导致
latency and high fees.
延迟和高额费用。
And second is hardware security and on-chain data privacy and decentralization brings
其次是硬件安全和链上数据隐私和去中心化带来的
data risks.
数据风险。
And the last one is unclear regulations and grid barrier and on-chain cooperation models
最后一个是监管和网格壁垒不明确以及链上合作模式
will block commercial closed loop.
会阻塞商业闭环。
And about opportunities, data ascentization connects energy, carbon assets, and finance
关于机遇，数据提升将能源、碳资产和金融联系起来
together with carbon revenue and inclusive finance.
以及碳收入和普惠金融。
We will balance the affordability and the long-term instantiability.
我们将平衡负担能力和长期可实例性。
That's all.
就这样。
Thanks, Kelly.
谢谢，凯利。
So since we are almost out of time, so let's ramp up with some takeaway.
既然时间快到了，我们就先来点外卖吧。
So yeah, I think the first takeaway is converging the hardware and the blockchain is not just
所以，是的，我认为第一个要点是融合硬件，而区块链不仅仅是
the idea or the concept.
想法或概念。
Yeah, we already see so many cool use cases.
是的，我们已经看到了很多很酷的用例。
And yeah, it's becoming the real design space.
是的，它正在成为真正的设计空间。
From the robot car, the AI robotics, the open source chipset, camera, the energy devices
从机器人汽车、人工智能机器人、开源芯片组、相机、能源设备
to serve the real community.
服务真正的社会。
And the second takeaway is moving from the device to the autonomous system.
第二个要点是从设备转向自治系统。
It's not the software or the hardware challenge, it's the coordination challenge.
这不是软件或硬件的挑战，而是协调的挑战。
So that is the way the Ethereum or the Web3 blockchain can play a very meaningful role.
这就是以太坊或 Web3 区块链可以发挥非常有意义的作用的方式。
It's not to put everything on-chain, but you need to by enabling the device with the identity,
这并不是要把所有东西都放在链上，而是需要通过身份来启用设备，
the trust, the verification, coordination, and also the interoperability.
信任、验证、协调以及互操作性。
And the last takeaway, I think maybe a deep message from today's panel is if we see the
最后一个要点是，我认为也许今天的小组传达的一个深刻信息是，如果我们看到
Ethereum was the first about the coordination, the asset, the finance, the capital, and the
以太坊是第一个关于协调、资产、金融、资本和
smart contract.
智能合约。
And next, the chapter may come to coordinate the machine, the device, the aging, the real-world
接下来，本章可能会协调机器、设备、老化、现实世界
infrastructure in the coming machine economy.
未来机器经济中的基础设施。
So thanks to all the panelists for giving us those very valuable insights and sharing.
感谢所有小组成员为我们提供了非常有价值的见解和分享。
And thanks to all to join this panel.
感谢大家加入这个小组。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Please take a photo before you leave the stage.
离开舞台前请合影留念。
Thank you everyone for sharing.
谢谢大家的分享。
While we get the stage set up for our last session, a quick note for those who may just
当我们为最后一次会议准备好舞台时，请为那些可能只是
have joined us.
已加入我们。
This gathering is hosted by Ethereum Application Guild, or EAG, a global non-profit collaborative
本次聚会由以太坊应用程序协会 (EAG) 主办，这是一个全球非营利合作组织
organization dedicated to advancing the innovation, adoption, and real-world impact of Ethereum
致力于推进以太坊的创新、采用和现实世界影响的组织
native applications.
本机应用程序。
We have now reached our final chapter.
我们现在已经到了最后一章。
What's next?
接下来怎么办？
The future of Ethereum applications.
以太坊应用程序的未来。
Please welcome Dr. Xiaofeng and Vitalik Buterin to the stage as they look ahead to the next
欢迎晓风博士和 Vitalik Buterin 上台展望下一个
stage of Ethereum, moving towards real-world deployment and adaptation.
以太坊阶段，迈向现实世界的部署和适应。
Now we have reached the final chapter of today's conference.
现在我们已经进入了今天会议的最后一章。
Please welcome Dr. Xiaofeng and Vitalik Buterin to the stage as they look ahead to the next
欢迎晓风博士和 Vitalik Buterin 上台展望下一个
stage of Ethereum, moving towards real-world deployment and adaptation.
以太坊阶段，迈向现实世界的部署和适应。
Please welcome.
请欢迎。
Let's give them a round of applause.
让我们给他们热烈的掌声。
Dear friends, welcome to the second session of Vitalik Buterin's talk show.
亲爱的朋友们，欢迎来到Vitalik Buterin第二期脱口秀节目。
Last year, we also held a talk show.
去年我们还举办过脱口秀节目。
So, Vitalik, would you like to say hello to everyone?
那么，Vitalik，你想跟大家打个招呼吗？
What should I say?
我应该说什么？
Hello everyone.
大家好。
Hello.
你好。
Everyone is very good.
每个人都很好。
Everyone is always good.
每个人总是好的。
Actually, before this, before we came on stage, there was a discussion about a combination
其实在这之前，在我们上台之前，有一个关于组合的讨论。
of intelligent hardware and blockchain.
智能硬件和区块链。
I also know that in recent weeks, Vitalik has seen a lot of companies and chips.
我也知道最近几周，Vitalik 见过很多公司和芯片。
Some companies and entrepreneurs related to chip and intelligent hardware manufacturing.
一些与芯片、智能硬件制造相关的企业和企业家。
I am also very curious.
我也很好奇。
I heard this news.
我听到这个消息了。
Why are you suddenly interested in these intelligent hardware and chips at this moment?
为什么这个时候突然对这些智能硬件和芯片产生了兴趣呢？
Why are you interested in these things?
你为什么对这些事情感兴趣？
What kind of interactions do you think there will be with Ethereum?
您认为与以太坊将会有什么样的互动？
I would like to invite you to talk about this topic first.
我想先请您来谈谈这个话题。
Okay.
好的。
We have recently started to discuss a lot of topics.
我们最近开始讨论很多话题。
We say that it is a full stack open source security.
我们说它是一个全栈开源安全。
Full stack is an application of every layer, including the application layer.
全栈是每一层的应用，包括应用层。
If it is a website, then the blockchain is also a layer.
如果是网站，那么区块链也是一层。
The operating system is also a layer.
操作系统也是一层。
The hardware is also a layer.
硬件也是一层。
There are many different layers.
有许多不同的层。
If any layer is not safe, then the whole system is not safe.
如果任何一层不安全，那么整个系统也不安全。
We have been saying that we should do something safe.
我们一直在说我们应该做一些安全的事情。
We don't need to be centralized.
我们不需要中心化。
But if we really want to do this, then we need to care about each layer.
但如果我们真的想这样做，那么我们需要关心每一层。
You can think about it.
你可以考虑一下。
I saw a lot of people saying that they are the owners of Ethereum.
我看到很多人说他们是以太坊的所有者。
If you have Ethereum, then how do you ensure the security of Ethereum?
如果你有以太坊，那么你如何保证以太坊的安全呢？
First, you have your wallet.
首先，你有你的钱包。
Second, you have your computer's operating system.
其次，您有计算机的操作系统。
Third, if you use hardware, then how can you be sure that your hardware is safe?
第三，如果你使用硬件，那么你如何确定你的硬件是安全的？
There are many applications that have been discussing this topic for the past two years.
过去两年有许多应用程序一直在讨论这个话题。
Everyone wants to use blockchain platforms to do more things in the real world.
每个人都想利用区块链平台在现实世界中做更多的事情。
This also depends on hardware.
这也取决于硬件。
The hardware layer is important no matter what we do.
无论我们做什么，硬件层都很重要。
It is not only about the security of Ethereum L1.
这不仅仅是关于以太坊 L1 的安全性。
In the second layer of Ethereum, some hardware needs to be accelerated for some calculations.
在以太坊的第二层中，一些硬件需要加速一些计算。
After all, the acceleration of hardware is one of the methods to solve the performance problem.
毕竟硬件的加速是解决性能问题的方法之一。
Maybe today, when blockchain Ethereum is a infrastructure,
也许今天，当区块链以太坊成为基础设施时，
it needs to support more applications.
它需要支持更多的应用程序。
It may also need to use some hardware to keep it safe or provide better efficiency and performance.
它还可能需要使用一些硬件来保证其安全或提供更好的效率和性能。
This is the topic we want to talk about.
这就是我们要讨论的话题。
Next, I noticed that you have been discussing this topic for a long time,
接下来，我注意到你们已经讨论这个话题很长时间了，
but I think it is a very important topic.
但我认为这是一个非常重要的话题。
We know that blockchain Ethereum has a very high threshold for ordinary users.
我们知道区块链以太坊对于普通用户来说门槛非常高。
Not only the wallet, but also the smart contract.
不仅是钱包，还有智能合约。
Not everyone has the ability to write a perfect smart contract.
并不是每个人都有能力编写完美的智能合约。
You have also mentioned the simplification of Ethereum.
您还提到了以太坊的简化。
Simplification is a fact.
简化是事实。
My understanding is to reduce the threshold of Ethereum application
我的理解是降低以太坊应用门槛
so that more people can use Ethereum conveniently.
让更多的人可以方便的使用以太坊。
This reminds me that we started from the computer.
这让我想起我们是从电脑开始的。
The original operating system of the computer is the command line.
计算机最初的操作系统是命令行。
Before Bill Gates, Bill Gates used the DAO operating system.
在比尔·盖茨之前，比尔·盖茨使用的是 DAO 操作系统。
The DAO operating system is a command line.
DAO 操作系统是一个命令行。
If the operating system is still the command line,
如果操作系统还是命令行，
I believe that 90% of the current computer users cannot use the computer.
我相信现在90%的电脑用户都不会使用电脑。
It is extremely difficult to learn.
学习起来非常困难。
Later, the browser appeared.
后来，浏览器出现了。
After the browser, there was the Windows graphics operating system.
在浏览器之后，出现了 Windows 图形操作系统。
As the threshold of the computer became lower and simpler,
随着计算机的门槛变得越来越低、越来越简单，
the operating process of the computer became simpler,
计算机的操作过程变得更加简单，
more and more people could use the computer.
越来越多的人可以使用计算机。
The biggest simplification came from the mobile Internet.
最大的简化来自于移动互联网。
Then the App appeared.
然后应用程序出现了。
We know that WeChat is a very complex system,
我们知道微信是一个非常复杂的系统，
but it is sealed into an App.
但它被封装在一个App中。
You only need to use one finger to operate WeChat.
只需一根手指即可操作微信。
That is to say, you can operate a certain function or program of the computer.
也就是说，你可以操作计算机的某种功能或程序。
Therefore, from this perspective,
因此，从这个角度来看，
we are very much looking forward to Ethereum being simplified more and more.
我们非常期待以太坊变得越来越简单。
Simplification, automation, or intelligentization.
简化、自动化或智能化。
We want to make it easier for more people to use Ethereum with just one finger.
我们希望让更多的人能够更轻松地用一根手指使用以太坊。
Of course, we are very much looking forward to this.
当然，我们对此非常期待。
I would also like to hear from you.
我也想听听你的消息。
Can you tell us about what you have mentioned
您能告诉我们您提到的内容吗
or what you are thinking of simplifying Ethereum?
或者你对简化以太坊有什么想法？
What is its journey and final goal?
它的历程和最终目标是什么？
I think the word simplification has two meanings.
我认为简化这个词有两个含义。
The first meaning is the iPhone simplification.
第一个意思是iPhone的简化。
You can see that you have a mobile phone.
可以看到你有手机。
It looks very simple to the user.
对于用户来说，它看起来非常简单。
You can press a button and know what it will do.
你可以按下一个按钮并知道它会做什么。
But behind the screen, there is a very complicated system.
但屏幕的背后，却隐藏着一个非常复杂的系统。
This is the first meaning.
这是第一个意思。
The second meaning is to simplify the very complicated system.
第二个含义是把非常复杂的系统简单化。
Both are important.
两者都很重要。
Why is the second meaning important?
为什么第二个含义很重要？
The second meaning is important
第二个意义很重要
because if a system is too complicated,
因为如果一个系统太复杂，
it means that there are very few people who can participate.
这意味着能够参与的人很少。
There are very few people who can participate.
能参与的人很少。
For example, the process of core development.
比如核心开发的流程。
You can say that a system is theoretically a trustluster.
你可以说，一个系统理论上是一个信任系统。
It doesn't need to trust people.
它不需要相信人。
But if there is a very, very complicated system in the core of this system,
但是如果这个系统的核心有一个非常非常复杂的系统，
there are only 200 or 50 people who know how to do it.
只有200或50人知道如何去做。
All people in the world still need to believe in those 50 people.
世界上所有人仍然需要相信这50个人。
So a system that is too complicated cannot be a trustluster.
因此，过于复杂的系统不可能成为信任体系。
So this is one thing.
所以这是一回事。
Another thing is the future of user experience.
另一件事是用户体验的未来。
I think the Minglin Bank and the current GUI have a lot of differences.
我觉得明林银行和现在的GUI有很多区别。
One difference is that the different users of the GUI are more useful.
一个区别是 GUI 对不同的用户来说更有用。
But the Minglin Bank also has its own advantages.
但明林银行也有自己的优势。
For example, a very important advantage is
例如，一个非常重要的优点是
that 50 years ago, at the beginning of the Minglin Bank,
50年前，明林银行成立之初，
there was a philosophy called Unix philosophy.
有一种哲学叫做 Unix 哲学。
Unix philosophy has a lot of parts.
Unix 哲学有很多部分。
But one of its parts is that
但它的一部分是
we should do a lot of simple things.
我们应该做很多简单的事情。
One operation of a user may use a lot of different systems at the same time.
用户的一项操作可能同时使用很多不同的系统。
It is possible that the input of a user will be input to the first system.
用户的输入有可能被输入到第一系统。
The output of the first system will become the input of the second system.
第一个系统的输出将成为第二个系统的输入。
The output of the second system will become the input of the third system.
第二个系统的输出将成为第三个系统的输入。
That is the concept of the pipe.
这就是管道的概念。
This concept has an advantage.
这个概念有一个优点。
In the era of GUI,
在GUI时代，
there are a lot of people who criticize or are not satisfied.
批评或不满意的人很多。
Some people will say that a number is a nonsense or a feudalism.
有人会说，数字是无稽之谈，是封建主义。
The natural result of a GUI is that
GUI 的自然结果是
you have a UI that is controlled by a company.
你有一个由公司控制的用户界面。
You live in a small universe of a company.
你生活在公司的一个小宇宙里。
Your digital life is controlled by a company.
您的数字生活由公司控制。
Unix philosophy is completely opposite.
Unix 的哲学是完全相反的。
There are many different cities.
有许多不同的城市。
Each city is made by a different company.
每个城市都是由不同的公司建造的。
They can operate each other through the Minglin Bank.
他们可以通过明林银行互相操作。
This is the third step.
这是第三步。
This is AI.
这就是人工智能。
Actually, we have started to pay more attention to AI in the Taiwan summit.
事实上，从这次台湾峰会上，我们已经开始更加关注人工智能了。
Last year, we opened the Kohaku team.
去年，我们成立了 Kohaku 团队。
They are a team that makes money.
他们是一支赚钱的团队。
Last month, the first version of the Kohaku came out at the FCC.
上个月，Kohaku 的第一个版本在 FCC 上发布。
They have said that
他们说过
they are going to release a version of Zhu Wang.
他们要发布朱旺的一个版本。
But after the Zhu Wang version,
但朱王版之后，
we all think that the concept of the current wallet
大家都认为现在钱包的概念
may disappear in two years.
可能会在两年内消失。
The future is AI.
未来是人工智能。
So we need to start thinking about AI wallet.
所以我们需要开始考虑人工智能钱包。
We need to start thinking about how to make AI wallet safe.
我们需要开始思考如何让AI钱包安全。
So we are thinking about the AI user interface more.
所以我们更多地考虑人工智能用户界面。
We found that AI is actually a Minglin Bank.
我们发现AI其实就是明林银行。
AI is you talking to a computer.
人工智能是你与计算机对话。
Using natural language.
使用自然语言。
Yes.
是的。
It is a Minglin Bank that uses natural language.
它是一个使用自然语言的铭林银行。
So in fact, the third generation can say that
所以其实第三代可以这么说
it also has the advantages of the second generation.
它还具有第二代的优点。
It has the advantages of the Minglin Bank.
具有明林银行的优势。
We can have a lot of different people,
我们可以有很多不同的人，
different companies, small cities.
不同的公司，小城市。
They can operate each other through the Minglin Bank.
他们可以通过明林银行互相操作。
But the user experience of this system will also be very good.
但是这个系统的用户体验也会非常好。
So in fact, if we do it well,
所以事实上如果我们做得好的话
we can combine the advantages of the Minglin Bank
我们可以结合明林银行的优势
and the advantages of the GUI.
以及 GUI 的优点。
So if we do it well,
所以如果我们做得好的话
the results may be particularly good.
结果可能会特别好。
But we need to do it well.
但我们需要把它做好。
Yes.
是的。
The operation of the Minglin Bank
明林银行的运作
can face a lot of developers,
可以面对很多开发商，
a lot of computer programs.
很多计算机程序。
But the APP is integrated into this APP by one company.
但是这个APP是被一家公司整合到这个APP里的。
So from a consumer benefit perspective,
所以从消费者利益角度来看，
of course,
当然，
a lot of developers and a lot of programs
很多开发者和很多程序
can be easily used by a consumer.
消费者可以轻松使用。
This is the biggest benefit of a consumer.
这是对消费者最大的好处。
If you can't do this,
如果你做不到这一点，
you have to simplify it and let everyone use it.
你必须简化它并让每个人都使用它。
Then it becomes an APP.
然后就变成了一个APP。
There are actually a lot of other developers behind this APP.
这个APP背后其实还有很多其他的开发者。
But it is integrated into a platform.
但它被集成到一个平台中。
So now,
所以现在，
AI is coming.
人工智能来了。
When AI comes,
当人工智能到来时，
there may be a reverse phenomenon
可能会出现相反的现象
that goes back to the Minglin Bank
可以追溯到明林银行
to operate a computer.
操作计算机。
Of course, the Minglin Bank at that time
当然，当时的明林银行
was not the Minglin Bank we used to learn.
不是我们以前学的明林银行。
Instead, it uses natural language.
相反，它使用自然语言。
When you say it,
当你说出来的时候，
the computer will move the data behind it.
计算机会将其后面的数据移动。
This is the biggest benefit of the Minglin Bank.
这是明林银行最大的好处。
Of course, this is what I look forward to.
当然，这也是我所期待的。
I look forward to doing this
我期待着这样做
using artificial language
使用人工语言
to help AI.
来帮助人工智能。
I also want to say that
我还想说
when we talk about the simplification of ETH,
当我们谈论 ETH 的简化时，
When it comes to the simplification of Ethereum,
当谈到以太坊的简化时，
I remember that in 2016,
我记得2016年的时候，
when DevCon was held in Shanghai
DevCon 在上海举行时
at the Global Development Conference of Ethereum,
在以太坊全球发展大会上，
there was already a discussion about simplification,
已经有关于简化的讨论，
such as simplifying the programming of smart contracts,
例如简化智能合约的编程，
and some tools or technical means.
以及一些工具或者技术手段。
At that time, I remember that two different technical development teams
当时我记得是两个不同的技术开发团队
discussed formal verification in 2016.
2016年讨论了形式验证。
Formal verification is to use formal verification
形式化验证就是使用形式化验证
to verify all the applications on Ethereum,
验证以太坊上的所有应用程序，
including all kinds of smart contracts,
包括各类智能合约，
to find its bugs,
找到它的错误，
to make it a very perfect smart contract.
使其成为一个非常完美的智能合约。
Now AI has come again.
现在AI又来了。
With AI and formal verification,
通过人工智能和形式化验证，
is it possible that any individual,
是否有可能任何个人，
even if he has no programming ability,
即使他没有编程能力，
he is not a computer engineer,
他不是计算机工程师，
he can also build his own smart contract
他还可以构建自己的智能合约
for his own purpose, for his own needs.
为了他自己的目的，为了他自己的需要。
This smart contract will indeed not have bugs,
这个智能合约确实不会有bug，
it will not be found by hackers,
它不会被黑客发现，
and it can run very well.
而且它可以运行得很好。
This is the premise.
这是前提。
Or from another angle,
或者从另一个角度来看，
formal verification,
形式验证，
we started to discuss ten years ago.
我们十年前就开始讨论了。
To this day, if we add AI,
直到今天，如果我们加上人工智能，
is it possible for those of us who have computer programming abilities
对于我们这些有计算机编程能力的人来说有可能吗
or those who do not have computer programming abilities
或没有计算机编程能力的人
to write their own smart contracts
编写自己的智能合约
and run them on Ethereum?
并在以太坊上运行它们？
Yes.
是的。
Formal verification is very important now.
形式验证现在非常重要。
In fact, writing this smart contract
事实上，编写这个智能合约
is a very important part.
是非常重要的一部分。
We may have talked a lot about it in 2016,
2016年我们可能已经讨论过很多次了，
because the attack on DAO took place in 2016,
因为 DAO 的攻击发生在 2016 年，
so everyone just realized the importance
所以大家才意识到重要性
of the smart contract security issue.
智能合约的安全问题。
But this year, the quad mythos came out.
但今年，四方神话出现了。
Many people were very surprised by this,
很多人对此感到非常惊讶，
and even very afraid.
甚至非常害怕。
According to my current understanding,
按照我目前的理解，
the quad mythos is indeed stronger than the previous AI,
四神神话确实比之前的AI更强，
but as everyone said, it also has some flaws.
但正如大家所说，它也有一些缺陷。
But we can't just look at the current quad mythos,
但我们不能只看当前的四方神话，
we need to look at the trend.
我们需要看看趋势。
The trend is that the quad mythos is much better than the AI of a year ago.
趋势是，四元神话比一年前的人工智能要好得多。
The AI of the next year will be much better than the quad mythos.
明年的人工智能将比四方神话好得多。
The AI of the year 2029,
2029 年的人工智能，
looking for various activities,
寻找各种活动，
may be very scary.
可能会很可怕。
So now I think the only way is
所以现在我认为唯一的办法是
that we need to use AI plus formal verification
我们需要使用人工智能加上形式化验证
plus more methods.
加上更多的方法。
This is a very safe code.
这是一个非常安全的代码。
There is no very serious activity code.
没有非常严肃的活动代码。
Now, because of the AI,
现在，因为人工智能，
it is almost possible now.
现在几乎有可能了。
Then, because of the AI's ability to look for various activities,
然后，由于人工智能能够寻找各种活动，
this will be necessary.
这是必要的。
So now we are at Lean Ethereum,
所以现在我们处于精益以太坊，
which is a team that is working on the next version of Ethereum.
这是一个正在开发以太坊下一版本的团队。
They are now working on the next version of Ethereum's POS.
他们现在正在开发以太坊 POS 的下一版本。
They have many goals.
他们有很多目标。
The first one is faster,
第一个比较快
the final time,
最后一次，
from now on, 16 minutes,
从现在开始，16分钟，
maybe 16 seconds, maybe 8 seconds, maybe less.
也许16秒，也许8秒，也许更少。
The second one is faster.
第二个更快。
Now, since last year,
现在，从去年开始，
all the things we are thinking about,
我们正在思考的所有事情，
the things we are developing now,
我们现在正在开发的东西，
we all say that it is necessary.
我们都说这是必要的。
The third one is more centralized,
第三个是比较集中的，
more safe.
更安全。
So they have a lot of needs.
所以他们有很多需求。
One of the things they are doing now
他们现在正在做的事情之一
is that they are using the Lean Consensus,
是他们正在使用精益共识，
which is the next version of the POS,
这是 POS 的下一个版本，
to prove that they are safe.
以证明他们是安全的。
This includes the signature of the two sides,
这包括双方的签名，
including the two sides' neighbor,
包括双方的邻国，
Stark,
斯塔克，
including the recursive Stark.
包括递归斯塔克。
So this includes a lot of complicated things.
所以这里面包含了很多复杂的事情。
Maybe two years ago,
也许两年前，
everyone thought that it was impossible
大家都认为这是不可能的
to prove such a complicated thing in a computerized way.
以计算机化的方式证明如此复杂的事情。
Maybe it was impossible forever.
也许永远不可能。
But now,
但现在，
because of the fast development of AI,
由于人工智能的快速发展，
these things are more possible.
这些事情更有可能。
So AI is now an increasingly important part
所以人工智能现在是一个越来越重要的部分
of our L1 core development.
我们的 L1 核心开发。
It is also very important
这也是非常重要的
to write the L1 core language.
编写L1核心语言。
Recently,
最近，
the time for various reviews
各种评论的时间
is getting more and more serious.
越来越严重了。
In fact,
实际上，
in the last two years,
在过去的两年里，
the L1 core language on the Internet is still good.
网上的L1核心语言还是不错的。
Recently,
最近，
more problems are in the L1 UI.
更多问题出现在 L1 UI 中。
Yes.
是的。
It is on the Internet.
它在互联网上。
AI can also help.
人工智能也可以提供帮助。
If we have AI,
如果我们有人工智能
for example,
例如，
you can search for the last year's safe tool.
你可以搜索去年的安全工具。
The safe tool is an unexpected tool.
安全工具是一个意想不到的工具。
If you use the safe tool through local AI,
如果你通过本地AI使用安全工具，
things will not happen.
事情不会发生。
So if you do it well,
所以如果你做得好的话
if you do it correctly,
如果你做得正确的话
AI,
人工智能，
because it can replace the third-party UI,
因为它可以替代第三方UI，
it can also help with security.
它还可以帮助提高安全性。
But AI also has its own security issues.
但人工智能也有其自身的安全问题。
So this is also what we are thinking about.
所以这也是我们正在思考的。
In the L1 core language,
在L1核心语言中，
the last year's Viper
去年的毒蛇
is the second
是第二个
L1 core language.
L1核心语言。
Solidity is the first,
坚固是第一，
Viper is the second.
毒蛇是第二个。
They have announced that
他们已经宣布
they are now supporting the implementation.
他们现在正在支持实施。
It is likely that their capabilities will become better.
他们的能力很可能会变得更好。
Solidity will also.
坚固也会。
Yes.
是的。
It will change.
它会改变。
This tool is not perfect.
这个工具并不完美。
It cannot solve all the problems immediately.
它不能立即解决所有问题。
But its ability
但其能力
and its ability to enhance AI
及其增强人工智能的能力
are indeed very powerful.
确实非常强大。
Yes.
是的。
We were just talking about
我们刚才正在谈论
how to make it possible for people
如何使人们成为可能
to write their own
写自己的
reliable smart contracts.
可靠的智能合约。
At the same time,
同时，
when you were discussing this topic,
当你们讨论这个话题的时候
you mentioned two topics that I would like to discuss with you.
你提到了两个我想和你讨论的话题。
One is quantum computing
一是量子计算
and anti-quantum computing.
和反量子计算。
Of course, this is
当然，这是
a paper published by Google.
谷歌发表的一篇论文。
Some people commented that
Some people commented that
in the paper published by Google,
在谷歌发表的论文中，
the most important risk
最重要的风险
is not Bitcoin,
不是比特币，
but the signature algorithm of Ethereum.
而是以太坊的签名算法。
What do you think about this?
您对此有何看法？
I have asked some cryptologists.
我问过一些密码学家。
Of course, the cryptologists gave me the opinion
当然，密码学家给了我意见
that this kind of solution
这种解决方案
is very difficult,
是非常困难的，
especially for quantum computing
特别是对于量子计算
like Bitcoin.
就像比特币一样。
This kind of algorithm is also very difficult.
这种算法难度也很大。
At the same time,
同时，
it is very difficult to
很难
counter quantum computing.
反量子计算。
Seven or eight years ago,
七、八年前，
I visited
我参观过
some very famous cryptologists in China.
中国一些非常著名的密码学家。
They have a lot of money
他们有很多钱
to study the encryption algorithm
研究加密算法
for anti-quantum computing.
用于反量子计算。
Because quantum computing
因为量子计算
decryption is not only
解密不仅是
aimed at crypto or blockchain.
针对加密货币或区块链。
The encryption algorithm in the world
世界上的加密算法
is actually facing such a threat.
居然面临着这样的威胁。
So, in fact, there is a lot of money
所以其实钱是很多的
invested in the development
投资开发
of those anti-quantum computing algorithms.
那些反量子计算算法。
For example, eight years ago,
例如，八年前，
I came across a concept called the encryption algorithm.
我遇到了一个叫做加密算法的概念。
At that time, I had the impression that
当时我的印象是
the higher one dies, the higher one rises.
死得越高，升得越高。
This is a process
这是一个过程
of balance between each other.
彼此之间的平衡。
There is no such phenomenon
没有这种现象
of one side falling.
一侧掉落。
What is your understanding of
你的理解是什么
the encryption algorithm for anti-quantum computing?
抗量子计算的加密算法？
Because we have already discussed
因为我们已经讨论过
a lot about quantum computing.
关于量子计算的很多内容。
There may be a threat to
可能存在威胁
Ethereum and Bitcoin,
以太坊和比特币，
and other different algorithms.
和其他不同的算法。
I think the less discussed one is
我认为讨论较少的一个是
the encryption algorithm
加密算法
for anti-quantum computing.
用于反量子计算。
What is the progress
进展如何
on this side?
在这一边？
I want to add something.
我想补充一些东西。
I have asked a
我问过一个
very creative
很有创意
central cryptologist.
中央密码学家。
I said,
我说，
what if
如果什么
anti-quantum...
反量子...
What if this happens?
如果发生这种情况怎么办？
For example, Bitcoin does have a lot of accounts.
例如，比特币确实有很多账户。
It may be too late to sign up.
报名可能已经太晚了。
If you want to change,
如果你想改变，
first of all, it is difficult
首先，这很难
to change the encryption algorithm.
更改加密算法。
In the process of changing,
在改变的过程中，
it did not respond in time.
它没有及时回应。
It did not update
没有更新
its wallet.
它的钱包。
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
I said,
我说，
it would cause a great loss
将会造成很大的损失
and an impact
和影响
and even make the whole system
甚至使整个系统
unbelievable.
难以置信。
I said, what if this happens?
我说，万一出现这种情况怎么办？
He said, it's easy to do.
他说，这很容易做到。
You can add another layer
您可以添加另一层
of encryption
加密的
on the existing encryption algorithm.
基于现有的加密算法。
You can add another layer
您可以添加另一层
of anti-quantum encryption algorithm.
抗量子加密算法。
Of course, this will affect the performance
当然，这会影响性能
and a lot of experience.
和很多经验。
But then,
但随后，
even if it happens
即使它发生了
three years later,
三年后，
it can be done again.
还可以再做一次。
This is
这是
the most
最
difficult
难的
solution.
解决方案。
I want you to
我要你
look at it from the perspective
从这个角度来看
of anti-quantum encryption
抗量子加密
and discuss
并讨论
the issue of anti-quantum encryption.
反量子加密问题。
Actually,
实际上，
anti-quantum encryption
反量子加密
is a more mature topic.
是一个比较成熟的话题。
We have known
我们已经知道
for more than 20 years
20多年来
that there are
有
two kinds
两种
of anti-quantum
反量子的
encryption technologies.
加密技术。
The first one is Jiu-Hashi.
第一个是九桥。
Jiu-Hashi includes
九桥包括
a lot of
很多
Jiu-Hashi
九桥
signature algorithms.
签名算法。
There is
有
Stark,
斯塔克，
the anti-quantum
反量子
encryption
加密
algorithm.
算法。
It is also
这也是
Jiu-Hashi.
九桥。
The second one is
第二个是
Jiu-Hashi
九桥
with some
与一些
quantum computers
量子计算机
and math
和数学
algorithms.
算法。
Nowadays,
如今，
a lot of people
很多人
use
使用
Lattice-based cryptography.
基于格的密码学。
Lattice-based cryptography
基于格的密码学
includes all FHEs
包括所有 FHE
and Jiu-Lattice.
和玖格。
So,
所以，
there are
有
two kinds.
两种。
Jiu-Hashi
九桥
has a signature
有签名
algorithm,
算法，
but
但
public keys
公钥
are not
不是
allowed.
允许。
Maybe 40 years ago,
也许40年前，
some
一些
mathematicians
数学家
proved that Jiu-Hashi
证明九桥
is not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
any kind of
任何种类的
public keys
公钥
including FHEs
包括 FHE
are not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
some
一些
kind of
有点儿
Lattice-based
基于格的
cryptography
密码学
is not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
some
一些
kind of
有点儿
Lattice-based
基于格的
cryptography
密码学
is not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
the two kinds of
两种
cryptography
密码学
are not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
some kind of
某种
Lattice-based
基于格的
cryptography
密码学
is not allowed.
是不允许的。
So,
所以，
some kind
某种
of
的
Lattice-based
基于格的
cryptography
密码学
is not
不是
can face AI's cryptography.
可以面对AI的密码学。
It must be hashed.
它必须被散列。
Why?
为什么？
Because hash is something that doesn't have any mathematical structure.
因为哈希是没有任何数学结构的东西。
A hash algorithm can be said to be a random algorithm.
哈希算法可以说是一种随机算法。
A cryptographer can say hash is a random oracle.
密码学家可以说哈希是随机预言。
A hash algorithm can't tell if it's a hash or a random algorithm.
哈希算法无法判断它是哈希算法还是随机算法。
So if there's only one safe thing, it's hash.
因此，如果只有一种安全的东西，那就是哈希。
So we hope that in L1, if we can do everything based on hash,
所以我们希望在L1中，如果我们能够基于哈希来做所有事情，
we can do everything based on hash.
我们可以基于哈希做任何事情。
But there's a drawback in these algorithms.
但这些算法有一个缺点。
The drawback of these algorithms is that the signatures of the current Ethereum
这些算法的缺点是当前以太坊的签名
are all based on the elliptic curve.
都是基于椭圆曲线。
A signature based on the elliptic curve is 65 bytes.
基于椭圆曲线的签名为 65 字节。
A signature based on hash is more than 2,000 bytes.
基于哈希的签名超过 2,000 个字节。
2 KB.
2 KB。
In fact, the lattice-based ones are about 0.6 and 3 kilobytes each.
事实上，基于点阵的大小分别约为 0.6 和 3 KB。
So they are also bigger.
所以它们也更大。
Then there's a ZK-Synarch.
然后是 ZK-Syncarch。
Now it's probably 500 megabytes.
现在可能是 500 兆字节。
A Stark is at least 300 KB more.
Stark 至少多 300 KB。
So we have to face some flow issues.
所以我们必须面对一些流量问题。
We know how to face these flow issues.
我们知道如何面对这些流量问题。
We have a way called aggregation.
我们有一种方法叫做聚合。
Aggregation means that if there's a block that needs a lot of signatures,
聚合意味着如果有一个区块需要很多签名，
that needs a lot of proofs,
需要大量的证据，
then a node that makes that block can make a proof by itself,
然后创建该块的节点可以自己进行证明，
a 300 KB proof.
300 KB 的证明。
This proof is a Stark.
这个证明是斯塔克的。
It proves all the other signatures and proofs.
它证明了所有其他签名和证明。
So no matter how many transactions,
所以无论有多少交易，
no matter how complicated the transactions are,
无论交易多么复杂，
it doesn't need to include all the signatures in the block.
它不需要包含块中的所有签名。
It only needs to include a 300 KB Stark.
它只需要包含 300 KB Stark。